<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Ramblingsinthesky.com</title>
    <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky" />
    <updated>2023-04-05T11:29:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ben Uecker</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Two Stork on the Beach</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/two-stork-on-the-beach.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/two-stork-on-the-beach.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-04-05T11:29:09-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" alt="" />
                    Here is a stylized photo of two storks on Smith Bay Beach (aka Lindquist Beach). I thought Google did a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog-pics.s3.amazonaws.com/ramblings/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" alt="2 storks on Lindquist Beach" width="3024" height="4032" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>Here is a stylized photo of two storks on Smith Bay Beach (aka Lindquist Beach). I thought Google did a good job on this photo. My wife took the original photo. We haven't seen too many storks lately. For awhile there we were seeing the same one every day we went.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>These Publii Themes are Not Working as I Intended</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/these-publii-themes-are-not-working-as-i-intended.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/these-publii-themes-are-not-working-as-i-intended.html</id>

        <updated>2023-04-05T11:05:39-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I've been trying to get a theme to look good on here but having a lot of difficulty. I'm not&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I've been trying to get a  theme to look good on here but having a lot of difficulty. I'm not sure what I am doing wrong. I am just looking for something simpel.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/switching-from-ghost-blog-to-cloudflare-pages.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/switching-from-ghost-blog-to-cloudflare-pages.html</id>

        <updated>2023-04-01T13:38:14-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages. I had a catastrophic event with my blog and its a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I am switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages. I had a catastrophic event with my blog and its a loss. I can still access the database but I have to extract everything by hand. I've started the process but it's been a nightmare. I had another blog that also had an upgrade disaster but after 2 years I was able to recover that one.</p>
<p>I love Ghost Blog but manually hosting shouldn't be this hard. I have had upgrade issues a few times in the past but at least I could recover. This last one was related to an upgrade to Mysql 8.0. Something to do with encoding. I have wasted hours trying to fix it. </p>
<p>With that behind me I am going to try use Publii to create the static site. Those posts are then uploaded to Github which in turn is then sent to Cloudfront pages. I have migrated several wordpress sites to static sites on S3. I thought I should try something different this time. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
