<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Ramblingsinthesky.com</title>
    <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky" />
    <updated>2023-04-05T20:00:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ben Uecker</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky</id>

    <entry>
        <title>2nd Bag of coffee from Esselunga and it still tasted great!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/2nd-bag-of-coffee-from-esselunga-and-it-still-tasted-great.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/2nd-bag-of-coffee-from-esselunga-and-it-still-tasted-great.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/6/esselunga-cafe1.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-04-05T20:00:50-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/6/esselunga-cafe1.jpg" alt="Esselunga Coffee" />
                    This was a bag of espresso ground coffee from Esselunga called Cafe Pueblo. My first experience with this company was&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/6/esselunga-cafe1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Esselunga Coffee" /></p>
                <p>This was a bag of espresso ground coffee from Esselunga called Cafe Pueblo. My first experience with this company was whole beaned. I really enjoyed the flavor the first time and was hoping this next bag would also taste great.</p>
<p>I really didn't know anything about the company when I purchased or drank the coffee. I just checked and it's a supermarket! Now this makes me feel stupid. Not that I am drinking and liking supermarket coffee from Italy but because it just hit me that the place we bought this from was called Essulunga!</p>
<p>We even had espressos and some strawberry dessert thing while we were there. We took the train from the Milan airport down just one stop and then walked till we found a supermarket. We wanted to bring home coffee and chocolates. We even were dragging our luggage with us!</p>
<p>Now back to the coffee. The coffee was purchased in May in Milan yet still maintained its freshness. The thing with most of these coffees is that the favors don't necessarily pop out at you. It's a great blend of a variety of coffees as an Italian roast.</p>
<p>It's very smooth with no bitterness detected. My next trip to Milan may require another stop at Esselunga.</p>
<p>I would also like to point out that this coffee would have been under €2. Great deal!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Home Roasting With a Popcorn Maker</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/home-roasting-with-a-popcorn-maker.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/home-roasting-with-a-popcorn-maker.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/5/sweet-marias1.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-04-05T15:31:24-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/5/sweet-marias1.jpg" alt="" />
                    I started my home roasting with an air popcorn maker. I probably should have waited as I have a 6&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/5/sweet-marias1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>I started my home roasting with an air popcorn maker. I probably should have waited as I have a 6 month supply of coffee at my house. However the urge finally overtook me and I ordered some green coffee beans from sweet <img src="https://ramblings-photos.s3.amazonaws.com/sweet-marias.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" data-is-external-image="true"></p>
<p>I am only able to make some batches of 50 grams each. This works out to about two cups of coffee for 8 minutes of work.</p>
<p>I have tried three different varieties and have made a half dozen batches so far. I haven't burnt any of the beans and so far each version has been amazing.</p>
<p>The roasting process just fills the house with these amazing smells. Some of it is chocolate and other times it smells like licorice. It's quite an amazing smell. Now one must remember that roasting coffee beans give off the same toxic chemical as microwave popcorn. Diacetyl is the culprit here. I plan on mitigating this in two different ways. First, my house is always open. One of those things awesome things about living in the tropics. The second thing is if I get addicted to roasting more I will then just start roasting outside. That would also solve my chafe problem. It isn't necessarily a problem for me as I am working with very small quantities right now.</p>
<p>I've roasted the coffee for as little as 5 minutes and as long as 8 minutes.</p>
<p>I like the darker roasts but prefer espresso or a strong cup of coffee. After roasting them in the popcorn maker I put them in a colander to cool off and to try and remove any chafe that I see. After about a minute I will drop them into my airtight glass container. I picked up a few different sizes at Ikea. You are supposed to give it the roasted beans a day before you grind and drink them due to the continued release of carbon dioxide. I think it's interesting because when you first out the beans in the container there is barely any smell. Come back later and open the container and wham the smell just rushes to your waiting nostrils. It becomes an addiction.</p>
<p>As I mentioned earlier each roast has turned out amazing. The flavors just explode from the coffee.</p>
<p>At home, I am a big coffee drinker. My wife does have a cup from time to time but really just sticks to having a shot added to her cinnamon rum on the weekends. I heat the cinnamon rum and froth it first. The coffee is made with Aeropress. For me, I use a shot of Aeropress on the weekdays and then I make flat whites on the weekends.</p>
<p>I like to try coffee both with and without milk to make sure I like the taste. I've yet to make cold press with my roasted coffee. Haven't really been around to try.</p>
<p>It's just so smooth and so full of flavor that I really think it's worth the extra time.</p>
<ol>
<li>Roast the beans</li>
<li>Grind the beans the next day</li>
<li>Make the coffee right after the grind</li>
<li>Enjoy the complexities of the coffee.</li>
</ol>
<p>I think my obsession with coffee started when we lived in Alpharetta and we took our first trip to santo Domingo about 5 years ago. I bought a bag of santo Domingo coffee and thought it was the best coffee I had ever tasted. I found out later that I could order it through a company out of Miami. When we moved to St Thomas I found out that Santo Domingo was sold in the stores! After buying them for awhile I ventured out to trying other Caribbean coffees. Yes, this was at the urging of my wife.</p>
<p>The next step was to bring some back from Puerto Rico. The coffees averaged $2 a lb there. That was about 60% cheaper than what I paid in St Thomas! With these cheap prices we decided that I should just buy a variety to try.</p>
<p>Our frequent visits made it easy to try the Puerto Rico coffees and I started understanding which coffees I liked and which ones were not so good.</p>
<p>I did this same thing on our next trip to Santo Domingo. I bought a whole suitcase full! This happens to be December of 2014. This also coincided with even more international travel. (Thank you low oil prices!)</p>
<p>We started to travel more internationally and the coffee prices were far cheaper than the states. I started with picking up several bags in Tahiti and New Zealand. After that I bought some whole bean at a rum festival. This led to buying a grinder. I use to have a grinder but it was cheap and it was a blade. I had no idea how awful it was at grinding till I got a burr Grinder many years later. I lost a lid in one of my many moves and never bothered to replace it.</p>
<p>Come to think of it I did try lots of different coffees in Austin but I was only using a drip coffee maker. Even the coffee maker makes a huge difference. My purchase of my Aeropress also took me much closer to the dark side.</p>
<p>Anyways, the coffee was dirt cheap in Spain (and it has to be some of the worst coffee in the entire world) and there too I picked up a suitcase full. By this time I was already on the fence if I should continue to purchase whole-bean or ground coffee. I had several bags and cans of coffee that were just not very good. Usually, it was due to bitterness.</p>
<p>The Italy trip saw me buying three bags of whole-bean coffee. Back home I started to flirt with cold press coffee. I had made it in the past but now I had a burr grinder(very cheap) and a better grasp on how I like my cold press coffee to taste. The key to cold press is to use a coarse ground and that meant grinding my own due to only buying espresso grinds on my trips.</p>
<p>Our next trip was to Paris. That would be the last trip where I purchased any ground coffee. China was also there but they didn't even have any instant coffee.</p>
<p>That brings us to today where I now am happily grinding my own. I'm going to seek out other opinions on my roasting skills. I am sure I am biased to my own particular tastes.</p>
<p>In one week we will be heading to Medellin, Columbia. I hope to bring back some green coffee beans from there. If I don't then the next trip to Puerto Rico is a coffee festival and I know for a fact I can get some during that event.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Two Storks on the Beach</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/two-stork-on-the-beach.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/two-stork-on-the-beach.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-04-05T15:27:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" alt="" />
                    Here is a stylized photo of two storks on Smith Bay Beach (aka Lindquist Beach). I thought Google did a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/3/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog-pics.s3.amazonaws.com/ramblings/PXL_20230403_221447027.MP-EFFECTS.jpg" alt="2 storks on Lindquist Beach" width="3024" height="4032" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>Here is a stylized photo of two storks on Smith Bay Beach (aka Lindquist Beach). I thought Google did a good job on this photo. My wife took the original photo. We haven't seen too many storks lately. For awhile there we were seeing the same one every day we went.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>These Publii Themes are Not Working as I Intended</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/these-publii-themes-are-not-working-as-i-intended.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/these-publii-themes-are-not-working-as-i-intended.html</id>

        <updated>2023-04-05T11:05:39-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I've been trying to get a theme to look good on here but having a lot of difficulty. I'm not&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I've been trying to get a  theme to look good on here but having a lot of difficulty. I'm not sure what I am doing wrong. I am just looking for something simpel.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/switching-from-ghost-blog-to-cloudflare-pages.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/switching-from-ghost-blog-to-cloudflare-pages.html</id>

        <updated>2023-04-01T13:38:14-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages. I had a catastrophic event with my blog and its a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I am switching from Ghost Blog to Cloudflare Pages. I had a catastrophic event with my blog and its a loss. I can still access the database but I have to extract everything by hand. I've started the process but it's been a nightmare. I had another blog that also had an upgrade disaster but after 2 years I was able to recover that one.</p>
<p>I love Ghost Blog but manually hosting shouldn't be this hard. I have had upgrade issues a few times in the past but at least I could recover. This last one was related to an upgrade to Mysql 8.0. Something to do with encoding. I have wasted hours trying to fix it. </p>
<p>With that behind me I am going to try use Publii to create the static site. Those posts are then uploaded to Github which in turn is then sent to Cloudfront pages. I have migrated several wordpress sites to static sites on S3. I thought I should try something different this time. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Review of UCC Brazil Luciana Whole Bean Coffee</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/review-of-ucc-brazil-luciana-whole-bean-coffee.html"/>
        <id>https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/review-of-ucc-brazil-luciana-whole-bean-coffee.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/4/ucc-brazil-luciana1.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-04-05T15:27:47-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/4/ucc-brazil-luciana1.jpg" alt="UCC Brazil Luciana" />
                    This is my review of UCC Brazil Luciana whole bean coffee. It's my second whole bean bag of coffee that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://buecker.github.io/ramblingsinthesky/media/posts/4/ucc-brazil-luciana1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="UCC Brazil Luciana" /></p>
                <p>This is my review of UCC Brazil Luciana whole bean coffee. It's my second whole bean bag of coffee that was purchased in Japan.</p>
<p>This particular bag was bought in a grocery store in Yokohama.</p>
<p>UCC Brazil Luciana might be the name of the coffee but all I know for sure is the company is called UCC. I found them on the web and they do have a place in Brazil. As far as purchasing more that I have no idea about it.</p>
<p>Let's get to what really matters. How does it taste? The answer to that question isn't very straightforward. It has a strong flavor but it's not actually bold. As a strong shot or as espresso it comes off with a tinge of bitterness with the complexities of chocolate. Sorry if it sounds weird but please don't let the word "bitterness" how you off. Think Starbucks burnt but without the aftertaste.</p>
<p>The beans were a dark French Roast and it was nowhere near my favorite espresso shot. However, as a latte it was amazing. For whatever scientific reason that I don't know, it became one of my favorites for homemade coffee drinks.</p>
<p>In the end I must say that I enjoy this coffee but keep in mind that it should be paired. It doesn't hold its own very well by itself.</p>
<p><em>Originally published on 11-15-2015. One of many posts I plan to restore from my old blog.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
