<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Ramblingsinthesky.com</title>
    <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com" />
    <updated>2024-09-29T10:16:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ben Uecker</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>WooCommerce site with Astra Died</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/woocommerce-site-with-astra-died.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/woocommerce-site-with-astra-died.html</id>

        <updated>2024-09-29T10:16:36-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    While I've never been a fan of WordPress, it does offer an affordable way to host an e-commerce site. Unfortunately,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>While I've never been a fan of <a href="https://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a>, it does offer an affordable way to host an e-commerce site. Unfortunately, my e-commerce site recently encountered significant issues. It was utilizing <a href="https://woocommerce.com/">WooCommerce</a> for the e-commerce functionality and <a href="https://wpastra.com/">Astra</a> for the theme. Lately, I've been experiencing difficulties with <a href="https://elementor.com/">Elementor</a> bundled with Astra. Just yesterday, the site became completely inaccessible. After some troubleshooting, I managed to get it running briefly before it crashed again. Even the recovery mode isn't functioning properly at this point.</p>
<p>This is a sign that I need to switch so something else. I plan to see if I can get <a href="https://medusajs.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">medusajs</a> to work. I tried for a short while yesterday but failed miserably. </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>SD Cards Do Not Like Crappy Power</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/sd-cards-do-not-like-crappy-power.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/sd-cards-do-not-like-crappy-power.html</id>

        <updated>2024-06-26T09:17:23-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I run my business website off of a raspberry pi. I had hosted in the cloud for years but decided&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I run my business website off of a raspberry pi. I had hosted in the cloud for years but decided to shift it to the home. I've been paying for a static IP for many years and well, why not?</p>
<p>I do have several things going against me.</p>
<ol>
<li>Power
<ol>
<li>Power is very expensive</li>
<li>Several power outages a month</li>
<li>Very poor power. Constant clicks and power spikes. Hard to hit 115V.</li>
<li>Hurricanes - When Irma hit we had no power for 90 days.</li>
<li>SD Cards do not like crappy power</li>
<li>Computer equipment does not like crappy power</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Hit and miss with the cable.
<ol>
<li>Speeds fluctuate a lot but not really an issue.</li>
<li>Due to the power outages sometimes the cable network runs out of fuel. I have starlink for.a backup but haven't spend enough time figuring out how to combine the IPV6 address with Cloudflare to serve the site on IPV4.</li>
<li>High season is in the winter and the cable internet really degrades from all the tourists.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Even with all that I figured why not. This morning I had to do another FSCK on the sdcard. I am sure it was from the latest power outage. While I do use battery backups and surge protectors they don't do the greatest job. In this instance the PI is being ran from my POE+ Switch which is actually on a transfer switch. When the power goes out it switches to a pure sine inverter connected to a deep cycle marine battery. I have surge protector on it but I can't run another battery backup in-between.</p>
<p>Overall, I have ran a few FSCK to fix the sd card and the original sd card was a no-name brand that did not last. Either way when I compare to hosting it on AWS the PI has paid for itself. I really want to move some more sites over but I think I need to get some solar+battery installed before I tempt it.</p>
<p>My main "server" or in other words my old intel nuc that acts as a server appears to have a failing NIC. I was thinking I would upgrade that and then put proxmox on it. I already use several docker containers on it. If I do that then I feel like I do not know what I should use the PI for? It's a PI4 and I have PI5 sitting unused. I had to downgrade to a 8 port POE switch after my 24 port died. I got it replaced but I don't want to install it until I am fully moved over to solar+battery.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Make Corn Tortillas From Scratch</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/how-to-make-corn-tortillas-from-scratch.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/how-to-make-corn-tortillas-from-scratch.html</id>
            <category term="corn tortillas"/>

        <updated>2024-04-21T11:58:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Making corn tortillas from scratch is a surprisingly simple process that yields delicious results. This is coming from someone who&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="markdown markdown-main-panel" dir="ltr">
<p data-sourcepos="1:1-1:159">Making corn tortillas from scratch is a surprisingly simple process that yields delicious results. This is coming from someone who always orders flour when going to a restaurant. </p>
<p data-sourcepos="1:1-1:159">Masa harina is what you need. Where we live there is a lot more Harina de maiz options than masa harina. Harina de maiz is cornmeal and is popular with Dominicans. Hence, we have lots of Dominicans living here. Harina de Maiz is not interchangeable with masa harina.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="1:1-1:159">Here's a basic rundown of what you'll need and how to do it:</p>
<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:16"><strong>Ingredients:</strong></p>
<ul data-sourcepos="5:1-8:0">
<li data-sourcepos="5:1-5:231">2 cups of Masa harina (corn flour): This is a specially treated flour made from dried field corn that's been nixtamalized (cooked in an alkaline solution). You can find it in most grocery stores, usually in the Latin American food section.</li>
<li data-sourcepos="6:1-6:12">1.5 cups of warm water (room temperature water if you live in a warm climate)</li>
<li data-sourcepos="7:1-8:0">Teaspoon of salt</li>
</ul>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:14"><strong>Equipment:</strong></p>
<ul data-sourcepos="11:1-16:0">
<li data-sourcepos="11:1-11:13">Mixing bowl</li>
<li data-sourcepos="12:1-12:15">Spoon or fork</li>
<li data-sourcepos="13:1-13:24">Rolling pin (optional)</li>
<li data-sourcepos="14:1-14:52">Tortilla press (optional, but makes things easier)</li>
<li data-sourcepos="15:1-16:0">Cast iron skillet or griddle</li>
</ul>
<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:17"><strong>Instructions:</strong></p>
<ol data-sourcepos="19:1-28:0">
<li data-sourcepos="19:1-20:0">
<p data-sourcepos="19:4-19:290"><strong>Mix the dough:</strong> In a large bowl, combine masa harina and salt. Gradually add 1 cup of water, mixing with a spoon or fork. The remaining half of cup you add slowly until a soft dough forms. You might need more or less depending on your climate. 1.5 cups is perfect for my tropical climate. The dough should be slightly sticky but not wet. .</p>
</li>
<li data-sourcepos="21:1-22:0"><strong>Portion the dough:</strong> Divide the dough into equal-sized balls, about the size of golf balls.
<ol data-sourcepos="19:1-28:0">
<li data-sourcepos="21:1-22:0">Some recipes have you rest the dough for 20-30 minutes. I do not do this.</li>
<li data-sourcepos="21:1-22:0">One site says it makes 8 corn tortillas. That was not good for me. The tortillas were too thick and they were not plyable. I shoot for 12 tortillas.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li data-sourcepos="25:1-26:0">
<p data-sourcepos="25:4-25:291"><strong>Press the tortillas:</strong> Here's where the tortilla press comes in handy. Place a dough ball between two pieces of plastic wrap and press down to form a thin disc. If you don't have a press, you can roll out the dough ball between two sheets of parchment paper to about 1/8-inch thickness. Just get a press. It saves so much time.</p>
</li>
<li data-sourcepos="27:1-28:0">
<p data-sourcepos="27:4-27:272"><strong>Cook the tortillas:</strong> Heat a cast iron skillet or griddle over medium heat. If you are using gas I need to keep mine at low. Place a tortilla in the hot pan for 10 seconds and then flip. This makes it a little more fluffy and cook for about 30-45 seconds per side, or until lightly browned and spotted. You can stack the cooked tortillas in a clean kitchen towel to keep them warm.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p data-sourcepos="29:1-29:9"><strong>Tips:</strong></p>
<ul data-sourcepos="31:1-35:0">
<li data-sourcepos="31:1-31:94">If the dough is too dry, add a little more water by the tablespoon until it becomes pliable.</li>
<li data-sourcepos="32:1-32:95">If the dough is too sticky, dust your hands with a little masa harina before working with it.</li>
<li data-sourcepos="34:1-35:0">Freshly made tortillas are best enjoyed warm, but they can also be stored in an airtight container at room temperature for up to 2 days. Reheat them in a skillet or microwave before serving.</li>
</ul>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Germans and Their Passive Aggressiveness</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/germans-and-their-passive-aggressiveness.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/germans-and-their-passive-aggressiveness.html</id>

        <updated>2024-02-11T10:53:07-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I was looking for the reason why Mainz was throwing tennis balls on the pitch today. Last time a team&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I was looking for the reason why Mainz was throwing tennis balls on the pitch today. Last time a team did this it had to do with ownership. A Google search led me to this awesomeness:</p>
<p>Germany 2024: rural youth singing “foreigners out” from a beer-drinking Lego carnival float</p>
<p>https://twitter.com/i/status/1756276399634059673<a href="https://twitter.com/i/status/1756276399634059673" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>2023 December Trip to New Zealand</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/2023-december-trip-to-new-zealand.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/2023-december-trip-to-new-zealand.html</id>

        <updated>2024-01-13T10:52:30-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This was our third time to New Zealand and first trip to the South Island. We stayed in Queenstown and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This was our third time to New Zealand and first trip to the South Island. We stayed in Queenstown and the purpose of the trip was to visit Milford Sound. It is a protected fjord that took several hours to get to. It exceeded our expectations by miles.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A 2013 Post about our Asian Tiger Mosquitos</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/a-2013-post-about-our-asian-tiger-mosquitos.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/a-2013-post-about-our-asian-tiger-mosquitos.html</id>

        <updated>2023-08-20T16:58:41-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We have had several Asian Tiger Mosquitos in our house up to about 2 weeks ago. They are HUGE compared&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We have had several Asian Tiger Mosquitos in our house up to about 2 weeks ago. They are HUGE compared to a normal mosquito. Just learned today from this article in <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/health/cdc-issues-warning-about-painful-virus-mosquitoes-2D11765769">nbcnews.com</a> that the mosquito may carry the dengue virus. Not only that virus but I guess a new virus from Africa as well. According to the article, <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/health/www.cdc.gov/chikungunya">Chikungunya virus</a>is also a very painful virus to get. It was found in Sint Maartin.</p>
<p>I am including a shot of one here but I may have to take a picture with my camera when I see another one. Fortunately, we have lots of geckos in the house and they do an amazing job of eating the bugs.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/ea/Aedes_Albopictus.jpg" alt="Asian Tiger Mosquitos" width="1080" height="733" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Post from 2015 about your 1st Trip to New Zealand</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/a-post-from-2015-about-your-1st-trip-to-new-zealand.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/a-post-from-2015-about-your-1st-trip-to-new-zealand.html</id>

        <updated>2023-08-20T16:56:32-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Note: This post is originally from 3/24/2015 and is from my ruined Ghost blog. I am reposting some of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Note: This post is originally from 3/24/2015 and is from my ruined Ghost blog. I am reposting some of the original content. I thought it would be fun to keep this one. We are going back to New Zealand for our 3rd time. This coming trip will be spent in Queenstown on the South Island.</p>
<p>This is just a short blurb about vacation. We recently got back from visiting Phoenix, Los Angeles, Tahiti, and Auckland, New Zealand.</p>
<ol>
<li>Tahiti was beautiful but not that much different than our own Caribbean islands. We went to Moorea for a day trip and that island is just stunning.</li>
<li>Getting to see even just one spring training game is awesome. I'm glad we go every year. This year we had to be at LAX the next day to fly out and so we drove to Los Angeles. The sunset was amazing. TuneIn radio worked 95% of the time and I would highly recommend it but just once.</li>
<li>New Zealand was even more beautiful than I expected and Auckland was an extremely modern city. I got to try a Flat White for the first time and just fell in love with the drink. We also went to Wahiki island off of Auckland and that provided us with even more beauty. Especially since we walked most of it. The wineries everywhere were top-notch.</li>
<li>A layover in Tahiti and Los Angeles on the way back wasn't too bad. In Tahiti, they took my travel corkscrew. First time in over 5 years I have had it taken on me and this was obviously my 2nd time in that airport! For Los Angeles, we just drove around near the water and checked out some of the scenery.</li>
</ol>
<p>I think sums it up. I have some amazing pictures and memories and very happy to have had the opportunity to take this trip.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>An Intro I wrote about My First Issues with Ghost Blog in 2013</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/an-intro-i-wrote-about-my-first-issues-with-ghost-blog-in-2013.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/an-intro-i-wrote-about-my-first-issues-with-ghost-blog-in-2013.html</id>

        <updated>2023-08-20T16:53:08-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Well, I just wrote over 2 pages of text and it was all wiped out by an accidental slip of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Well, I just wrote over 2 pages of text and it was all wiped out by an accidental slip of the mouse button. Guess there is no auto-save feature? I will have to check that out.</p>
<p>Lets see if I can shorten this:</p>
<p>Ghost is a new blogging platform and I didn't really have the time (I technically still don't) to try and install it. It has taken a solid 1.5 hours to get it up and running on my little server but it seems to be working.</p>
<p>There are 2 possible issues. The first is I am not sure if I am saving this in mysql or sqlite. It is suppose to be mysql. The second is the upstart functionality. When I reboot my server I can't seem to verify ghost will restart. Again, this is something I will have to test later.</p>
<p>Lastly, this is being housed on an atom server running on Ubuntu 13.10.</p>
<p>I repurposed an Acer Veriton with an atom processor. Replaced the expensive fan and added an SSD and doubled the memory. It also serves as a remote desktop host with virtualbox running an XP guest. I also occasionally use it to stream video to the TV. It sits behind the TV and is silent. You may think that putting an SSD in it is overkill but when you are paying 52.5 cents (soon to go up another 2.5 cents) per Kwh you would also be doing everything to reduce your electricity costs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hisense Soundbar Firmware</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/hisense-soundbar-firmware.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/hisense-soundbar-firmware.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/media/posts/12/Hisense-soundbar.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-08-19T14:22:02-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/media/posts/12/Hisense-soundbar.png" alt="Hisense Soundbar" />
                    I never found any Hisense soundbar firmware but I did find a reddit post on how to factory reset the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/media/posts/12/Hisense-soundbar.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Hisense Soundbar" /></p>
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog-pics.s3.amazonaws.com/ramblings/Hisense-soundbar.png" alt="Hisense Sondbar" width="997" height="264" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<p>I never found any Hisense soundbar firmware but I did find a reddit post on how to factory reset the sound bar. Volume Down + Power. Hold it down until the light starts to flash.</p>
<p>My soundbar had two issues. The Hisense Soundbar would not turn off and after a few minutes it went super quiet. I did the standard troubleshooting and then opened a ticket with Hisense. It took them just a day or two to send a text message asking for a pic of the label. I originally did the chat support.</p>
<p>A week goes by and I reach out to them again. They say I have to ship it in. I did not have the original box but I did find a box it would fit in. However, it would have cost me close to $30 to ship it out.</p>
<p>The positive of this situation is either 1. don't buy hisense again (our tv is hisense also) or 2. thank heavens I don't have to pay to ship it back to get it fixed.</p>
<p>The negative is that Hisense support should have suggested I hit those two buttons. They did ask me to unplug and plug it back in.  This is huge mistake on their part. It would have cost them time and money to press those two buttons and ship it back. You know that's all they would have done.</p>
<p>The old saying "You get what you paid for" lives on. Here is verifiable proof.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Austin FC Should Care More About Tournaments</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Uecker</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ramblingsinthesky.com/austin-fc-should-care-more-about-tournaments.html"/>
        <id>https://ramblingsinthesky.com/austin-fc-should-care-more-about-tournaments.html</id>

        <updated>2023-07-23T17:52:59-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Just a gripe. I would like to see Austin FC care more about tournaments. First game of Leagues Cup and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Just a gripe. I would like to see Austin FC care more about tournaments. First game of Leagues Cup and they lose easily. For the Concacaf tournament they lost to a bunch of part time footballers in Haiti. That's awful.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
